# Bardia Heydari

# Site Reliability Engineer & Software Engineer

+989384605300

bardia.heydarinejad@gmail.com

github.com/k3rn3l-p4n1c

in linkedin.com/in/bardiaheydarinejad

#### **ABOUT ME**

In addition to my 3 years of experience in Site Reliability Engineering, I also have a solid background in Backend Development and Software Engineering (+5 years). I am experienced with cloud providers and cloud-native architectures. My experience includes designing, implementing, and maintaining high-scale microservices. Additionally, I have experience in people management for more than 1 year.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Programming Language: Golang, Python, C#, JavaScript, Scala

Database: PostgreSQL, Elasticsearch, Redis, Mongo, Cassandra, RabbitMQ

Web Framework: Django, DRF

Monitoring: Prometheus, Grafana, StatsD

Automation: Gitlab-Cl, Ansible, Helm

Cloud: Kubernetes, Docker, LinkerD, Traefik, CloudFlare, Azure

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Tech Lead at Sindibad

Sindibad is Iraq's first online travel agency. As a startup, Sindibad provides localization solutions to make flight booking more convenient. (Website: <a href="sindibad.iq">sindibad.iq</a>)

Nov 2021 - Present

- Adopt DevOps culture in the organization by mentoring backend developers, building and managing the infrastructure team, and convincing stakeholders.
- Direct backend and infrastructure teams to achieve 95% reliability for core services.
- Increase technical team delivery by 50% by monitoring team velocity and retro sessions.
- Improve application conversion rate by 10% by identifying and eliminating technical debt that affects the business.
- Negotiated with Product and Business partners to balance technical tasks and feature development capacity.

**Skills**: Site Reliability Engineering · Kubernetes · Microservice Architecture · Prometheus.io · Microsoft Azure · Docker · Team Leadership · Technical Leadership · Gitlab Cl · C# · .NET Core · Software Engineering · Agile Methodologies · Team Building · Cloudflare · DevOps

# Senior Site Reliability Engineer at Divar

Apr 2021 - Nov 2021

With 45 million monthly active users, Divar is Iran's leading classified advertisement service. (Website: divar.ir)

- Coordinated the SRE Chapter's weekly meetings and Coached junior SREs.
- Maintained a variety of services with more than 10K requests per second.
- Achieved a performance boost in the search API to handle 5K RPS on 1M documents by redesigning the indexing of Elasticsearch.

**Skills**: Prometheus.io · Golang · Kubernetes · Microservice Architecture · Gitlab Cl · Docker · Software Engineering · Web Development · Linux · Git · Ansible · Elasticsearch · DevOps · Gitlab-Cl

#### Cafe Bazaar

Apr 2018 - Apr 2021

With more than 44 million active users, Café Bazaar is Iran's leading Android app store. (Website: cafebazaar.ir)

#### Site Reliability Engineer in Infrastructure Team

Sep 2019 - Apr 2021

- Developed and maintained the indoor API gateway which is handling 30K requests per second.
- Directed to eliminate 99% of false alarms in the entire backend by monitoring the monitoring system, and directed the chapter backend to produce a weekly report on their progress in monitoring maturity.
- Set up a governance system to check for bad patterns and make a significant impact on the reliability of microservices and detected more than 30 critical issues around the company.

**Skills**: Prometheus.io · Golang · Kubernetes · Microservice Architecture · Gitlab CI · Docker · Software Engineering · Linux · Git · Ansible · DevOps · Gitlab-CI

#### Software Engineer in Product Team

Apr 2018 - Sep 2019

- Designed and Implemented microservices written in Golang and for responding to 5 million daily unique visitors.
- Reduced the complexity of backend architecture by redesigning a stack of 5 extra fine-grained microservices into one service with the right size.

**Skills**: Prometheus.io · Golang · Kubernetes · Microservice Architecture · Python · Gitlab Cl · Docker · Agile Methodologies · Software Engineering · Web Development · Linux · Git · SQL · Django · Python

# Backend Engineer at Medrick FZE

Nov 2016 - Apr 2018

Involved in game center and social platform for gamers project named Ariogames.

- Developed ReSTful web services with Python and Scala and delivered a high number of features in a short time to meet deadlines.
- Refactored a big monolith web application into 7 microservices.
- Implemented CI/CD with Docker, Drone, Ansible, and other tools for continuous deployments.
- Improved response time from 3 seconds to 200 milliseconds by rewriting queries and cache policies in a critical API.

**Skills**: Microservice Architecture · Python · Gitlab CI · Docker · Nginx · Agile Methodologies · Software Engineering · Web Development · Linux · Git · SQL · Django · Scala · Ansible · PostgreSQL · Django REST Framework · Python

# Full Stack Developer at Irsapardaz

Sep 2014 - Nov 2016

Worked on a variety of projects. The most notable one was Mr. Football which was a football fantasy and football forecasting game.

- Developed ReSTful web services with Python (Django framework).
- Implemented the Android Application using Java.
- Create web crawlers using Scrapy.

**Skills:** C# · Python · Scrapy Framework · Web Crawling · Software Engineering · Web Development · Android Development · Java · Git · SQL · Django · PostgreSQL · Python

# **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Engineering (BEng), Computer Software Engineering Iran University of Science and Technology 2013 – 2017